<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Me on Mmoumni</title><link>https://mmoumni.com/</link><description>Recent content in About Me on Mmoumni</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmoumni.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend Engineering from the first Principles</title><link>https://mmoumni.com/posts/backend-engineering-from-the-first-principles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmoumni.com/posts/backend-engineering-from-the-first-principles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this Era of AI, I often find myself reflecting on the software engineering field. I’ve observed several emerging patterns among new software engineers. Although i’m still a junior, I definitely see myself as part of that group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New coming engineers are heavily relying on AI tools; however, they haven’t spent enough time building things that would give them the experience and knowledge needed to use those tools with real confidence. I’m referring to the core fundamentals of software engineering not frameworks or technologies that shift every few months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why i don't watch football anymore</title><link>https://mmoumni.com/posts/why-i-dont-watch-football-anymore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmoumni.com/posts/why-i-dont-watch-football-anymore/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-i-dont-watch-football-anymore"&gt;Why i don&amp;rsquo;t watch football anymore&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong i’ve been a football fan since I was 6 years old. I started by watching matches from our local league in morocco as well as games of our national team. I was obsessed with the sport: team histories, player’s names, and famous figures in the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I got older, I began following international leagues such as la liga in spain and the Premier league in UK, along with major international competitions like the world cup and the African Cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Social Dilemma</title><link>https://mmoumni.com/posts/the-social-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmoumni.com/posts/the-social-dilemma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I think about this subject every now and then, usually when i realize how much time i&amp;rsquo;ve been spending on social media. I keep asking myself why i can&amp;rsquo;t stop chekcing those apps. it feels like i&amp;rsquo;m missing something important, but in reality it&amp;rsquo;s just my brain craving a quick dopamine hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted my facebook and instagram accounts multiple times, only to return again. it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to cut myself off completely. Every time i try, it feels like i&amp;rsquo;m disconnecting from what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the world, especially in my field &amp;ndash; software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>what I learned from the reimplementation of ping command in C</title><link>https://mmoumni.com/posts/reimplementation-ping-command-in-c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmoumni.com/posts/reimplementation-ping-command-in-c/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always struggled to fully grasp the networking side of software development — especially when it comes to network programming concepts like sockets, binding, TCP/IP, and protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to take on the challenge and fill in the gaps in my understanding. To do that, I chose to reimplement three well-known networking commands: &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;traceroute&lt;/code&gt;, and a simplified version of &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series of articles, I’ll explain each command in detail — its use case and how it works under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>