<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Mmoumni</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8080/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Mmoumni</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building the BotolaPro Fantasy App Part2: Build the Scraper Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part2-build-the-scraper-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part2-build-the-scraper-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part2-build-the-scraper-service&#34;&gt;Building the BotolaPro Fantasy App Part2: Build the Scraper Service&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand what this article is about, checkout the previous post at:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mmoumni.com/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part1-scrapping-the-base-data/&#34;&gt;https://mmoumni.com/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part1-scrapping-the-base-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous article, I discussed the high-level architecture of the entire application. In this article, I will focus on the scraper service.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;system-design&#34;&gt;System Design:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid distracting myself with too many actions that the scraper API could support, I chose to start small and extend it as needs arise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the BotolaPro Fantasy App Part1: Scrapping the Base Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part1-scrapping-the-base-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/posts/building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part1-scrapping-the-base-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-the-botolapro-fantasy-app-part1-scrapping-the-base-data&#34;&gt;Building the BotolaPro Fantasy App Part1: Scrapping the Base Data&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are following my previous blogs, you may have noticed that i wrote a blog post about why i stopped watching football. You might be thinking: what is this guy doing? He Said he stopped watching football, and now he’s trying to build football game. Let me clarify why i’m doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My main Goal is to learn about mobile application development. While exploring ideas, I realized that there is no fantasy app for the Moroccan Botola Pro League. I thought this could be a good exercise to apply the skills I will learn during my mobile development journey, and it also seemed quite challenging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backend Engineering from the first Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/posts/backend-engineering-from-the-first-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/posts/backend-engineering-from-the-first-principles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Era of AI, I often find myself reflecting on the software engineering field. I’ve observed several emerging patterns among new software engineers. Although i’m still a junior, I definitely see myself as part of that group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New coming engineers are heavily relying on AI tools; however, they haven’t spent enough time building things that would give them the experience and knowledge needed to use those tools with real confidence. I’m referring to the core fundamentals of software engineering not frameworks or technologies that shift every few months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
